<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gin on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/gin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gin on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:29:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/gin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shoegaze</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shoegaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:29:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shoegaze/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A multi-layered cocktail with fruit, spice, and juniper working in tandem to let you experience a Wall of Flavor.
1 ½ oz London Dry Gin* 1 oz Szechuan Peppercorn-infused Byrrh Quinquina 1 oz Strawberry Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a fresh strawberry.
*Recommended: Bombay Sapphire
Szechuan Peppercorn-infused Byrrh Quinquina ½ cup Szechuan Peppercorns, crushed 750ml bottle Byrrh Quinquina Combine the Szechuan Peppercorns and the Byrrh in a quart-sized Mason jar and infuse for 48 hours, agitating daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shieldmaiden</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shieldmaiden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:26:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shieldmaiden/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail An adventurous Nordic-inspired riff on the Gimlet that incorporates the gentle cooling qualities of sage into the harsher tones of caraway and citrus.
1 oz Aquavit* 1 oz London Dry Gin** 1 oz Lemon-Sage Cordial ¼ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lemon wheel and a sage leaf.
*Recommended: Linie, Krogstad **Recommended: Fords, Bombay Dry, Broker’s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port Royal</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/port-royal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:13:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/port-royal/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Bracing, tannic, and slightly tropical, this cocktail is an imaginary venture to the history-rich docks of Jamaica in the late 1600’s.
1 ½ oz Ceylon Tea-infused London Dry Gin* ½ oz Sweet Aged Rum** ¾ oz Toasted Coconut Honey ¾ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Fiction</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/historical-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:25:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/historical-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A floral, refreshing cocktail that captures both the imagination and the senses.
1 ½ oz Gin* ½ oz Rosebud-infused Aquavit** 12 drops of Suze Gentian Liqueur*** 1 oz Raspberry Cordial ¾ oz lemon juice ½ oz egg white Add all ingredients to shaker, perform dry shake until egg white is properly frothed. Add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Strain into a chilled coupe glass. Garnish with bitter hearts (use an eye-dropper bottle filled with Angostura Bitters to place drops on the foam, and then drag a toothpick through them from one side through the other to make a heart shape) and rosebuds floated on the foam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flat Earth</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:17:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail An earthy, restorative sour with complexity that’ll make you question your own sanity.
1 ½ oz Gin* ¾ oz 80-proof Orange Liqueur** ¾ oz Roasted Walnut Orgeat ½ oz Beet Shrub ½ oz lemon juice 8 dashes (8 ml) Habanero Tincture Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lemon wheel.
*Recommended: Vitae Modern Gin, Aviation, Botanist, Plymouth **Recommended: Vitae Orange Liqueur, Cointreau</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
