<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spicy on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/spicy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spicy on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:03:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/spicy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Packmule</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/packmule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:03:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/packmule/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spicy, smoky, loaded take on the Mule.
2 oz Mezcal* ¾ oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ½ oz lime juice 15 dashes (15 ml) Habanero Tincture 2 ½ oz Ginger Beer** Add all ingredients except Ginger Beer to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Add Ginger Beer to the shaken cocktail. Double-strain over new ice in copper or tin mule mug. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some Cayenne Salt (equal parts kosher salt and cayenne pepper)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luchador</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/luchador/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:44:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/luchador/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A light-hearted prize-fighter that will win over almost any modern drinker.
1 ½ oz 100% Agave Blanco Tequila* ¾ oz Ancho Reyes Chili Liqueur ¾ oz lime juice ¾ oz Prickly Pear Cactus ¼ oz Ginger Syrup Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flat Earth</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:17:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail An earthy, restorative sour with complexity that’ll make you question your own sanity.
1 ½ oz Gin* ¾ oz 80-proof Orange Liqueur** ¾ oz Roasted Walnut Orgeat ½ oz Beet Shrub ½ oz lemon juice 8 dashes (8 ml) Habanero Tincture Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lemon wheel.
*Recommended: Vitae Modern Gin, Aviation, Botanist, Plymouth **Recommended: Vitae Orange Liqueur, Cointreau</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
