<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sour on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/sour/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sour on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:30:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/sour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zapotechnica</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/zapotechnica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:30:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/zapotechnica/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Fruity and complex, this smoky crowd-pleasing sour goes down way too easy.
2 oz Mezcal* ¼ oz Chartreuse Yellow 1 oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ¾ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.
*Recommended: Del Maguey Vida, El Silencio, Creyente Joven, Banhez Joven Espadín y Barril</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inca Trail</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/inca-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:28:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/inca-trail/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A polished version of the tart classic Pisco Sour that will transport your senses straight to the Andes.
2 oz Peruvian Pisco* ¾ oz Lime Cordial ½ oz lime juice ½ oz egg white Add all ingredients to shaker, perform dry shake until egg white is properly frothed. Add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Strain into a chilled coupe glass. Garnish with nutmeg grated over the foam.
*Recommended: La Diablada, Macchu Pisco</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flat Earth</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:17:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail An earthy, restorative sour with complexity that’ll make you question your own sanity.
1 ½ oz Gin* ¾ oz 80-proof Orange Liqueur** ¾ oz Roasted Walnut Orgeat ½ oz Beet Shrub ½ oz lemon juice 8 dashes (8 ml) Habanero Tincture Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lemon wheel.
*Recommended: Vitae Modern Gin, Aviation, Botanist, Plymouth **Recommended: Vitae Orange Liqueur, Cointreau</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appaloosa</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/appaloosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:40:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/appaloosa/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spicy, lively sour with a velvety mouthfeel and a ‘green’, vegetal flavor profile.
1 ½ oz 100% Agave Reposado Tequila* ¾ oz Ancho Reyes Verde Chili Liqueur 1 oz lime juice ½ oz Pepita Orgeat Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
