<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spring on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/spring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spring on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:45:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/spring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stowaway</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/stowaway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:45:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/stowaway/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail This beach-y, fruity cocktail is a light-hearted crowd-pleaser that evokes the feeling of a Piña Colada - but without all the mess.
1 ½ oz Coconut Oil-washed Potato Vodka* ½ oz Dry Curaçao** ¾ oz Guava ¾ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in a Collins glass and garnish with a dehydrated lime wheel and a paper cocktail umbrella.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Song Bird</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/song-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:40:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/song-bird/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A visually stunning, fruity and floral Daiquiri variation that will sing itself onto your Summer Favorites shortlist.
2 oz ‘White’ Rum* ¾ oz lime juice ¾ oz Blueberry-Lavender-Mint Cordial small pinch of salt Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lime peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shoegaze</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shoegaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:29:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shoegaze/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A multi-layered cocktail with fruit, spice, and juniper working in tandem to let you experience a Wall of Flavor.
1 ½ oz London Dry Gin* 1 oz Szechuan Peppercorn-infused Byrrh Quinquina 1 oz Strawberry Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a fresh strawberry.
*Recommended: Bombay Sapphire
Szechuan Peppercorn-infused Byrrh Quinquina ½ cup Szechuan Peppercorns, crushed 750ml bottle Byrrh Quinquina Combine the Szechuan Peppercorns and the Byrrh in a quart-sized Mason jar and infuse for 48 hours, agitating daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junction Paloma</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/junction-paloma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:08:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/junction-paloma/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Salty, refreshing and effervescent, this non-traditional take on the Mexican classic is sure to be a crowd-pleaser.
1 ½ oz 100% Agave Blanco Tequila* ½ oz Aperol ½ oz lime juice ¾ oz Salted Grapefruit Cordial 1 oz still water Assemble all ingredients, add ice, then carbonate**. Shake, then strain into a champagne flute. No garnish.
* Recommended: Lunazul Blanco, Altos Olmeca Blanco, Espolòn Blanco, Herradura Silver ** Note: I use the Perlini Cocktail Cabonation System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monkey Island</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/monkey-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:53:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/monkey-island/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A fruity yet spirit-forward cocktail with tropical notes that blur the imaginary lines dividing the seasons.
2 oz Blended Speyside Scotch* ½ oz Tempus Fugit Crème de Banane ½ oz Toasted Coconut Honey 6 dashes (6 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass with a large cube. Garnish with a dehydrated lime wheel.
*Recommended: Monkey Shoulder</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Fiction</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/historical-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:25:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/historical-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A floral, refreshing cocktail that captures both the imagination and the senses.
1 ½ oz Gin* ½ oz Rosebud-infused Aquavit** 12 drops of Suze Gentian Liqueur*** 1 oz Raspberry Cordial ¾ oz lemon juice ½ oz egg white Add all ingredients to shaker, perform dry shake until egg white is properly frothed. Add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Strain into a chilled coupe glass. Garnish with bitter hearts (use an eye-dropper bottle filled with Angostura Bitters to place drops on the foam, and then drag a toothpick through them from one side through the other to make a heart shape) and rosebuds floated on the foam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Hell to Breakfast</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/from-hell-to-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:22:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/from-hell-to-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>A hint of subtle spice lingers just underneath the surface of this rejuvenating and herbaceous sour that offers more with each sip.
1 oz 100-proof Rye Whiskey* ¾ oz Bénédictine D.O.M. ½ oz Luxardo Maraschino ¾ oz lemon juice 6 dashes (6 ml) St. Elizabeth’s Allspice Dram Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Sail</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/age-of-sail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:32:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/age-of-sail/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A boozy cane spirit cocktail with a delicate floral essence and complex undertones of bittersweet citrus.
1 ½ oz Haitian Rhum* 1 ½ oz Contratto Bianco ¼ oz Amaro Montenegro shy ¼ oz Pomegranate Grenadine 3 dashes (3 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into chilled coupe glass. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
