<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Herbal on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/herbal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Herbal on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:29:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/herbal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shoegaze</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shoegaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:29:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shoegaze/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A multi-layered cocktail with fruit, spice, and juniper working in tandem to let you experience a Wall of Flavor.
1 ½ oz London Dry Gin* 1 oz Szechuan Peppercorn-infused Byrrh Quinquina 1 oz Strawberry Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a fresh strawberry.
*Recommended: Bombay Sapphire
Szechuan Peppercorn-infused Byrrh Quinquina ½ cup Szechuan Peppercorns, crushed 750ml bottle Byrrh Quinquina Combine the Szechuan Peppercorns and the Byrrh in a quart-sized Mason jar and infuse for 48 hours, agitating daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shieldmaiden</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shieldmaiden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:26:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shieldmaiden/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail An adventurous Nordic-inspired riff on the Gimlet that incorporates the gentle cooling qualities of sage into the harsher tones of caraway and citrus.
1 oz Aquavit* 1 oz London Dry Gin** 1 oz Lemon-Sage Cordial ¼ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lemon wheel and a sage leaf.
*Recommended: Linie, Krogstad **Recommended: Fords, Bombay Dry, Broker’s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Puppet</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shadow-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:24:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shadow-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A dark, moody tipple with rich botanical undertones and a hint of menthol on its finish.
1 ½ oz Rye Whiskey* ¾ oz Cardamaro** ½ oz Pedro Ximenez Sherry*** shy ¼ oz Fernet Branca 4 dashes (4 ml) Peychaud’s Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass over new ice. Garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Hell to Breakfast</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/from-hell-to-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:22:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/from-hell-to-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>A hint of subtle spice lingers just underneath the surface of this rejuvenating and herbaceous sour that offers more with each sip.
1 oz 100-proof Rye Whiskey* ¾ oz Bénédictine D.O.M. ½ oz Luxardo Maraschino ¾ oz lemon juice 6 dashes (6 ml) St. Elizabeth’s Allspice Dram Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farmers Tan</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/farmers-tan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:08:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/farmers-tan/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A refreshingly acidic pick-me-up to ease you through the hottest days of Summer.
2 oz Lemongrass-infused Corn Moonshine* 1 oz Watermelon Shrub ¾ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lime wheel.
*Recommended: Belle Isle Moonshine
Lemongrass-infused Corn Moonshine 750ml bottle Corn Moonshine 8 stalks of lemongrass Slice the lemongrass into small pieces, then combine with the Moonshine in a quart-sized Mason jar and let infuse for three days, agitating daily.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
