<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rum on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/rum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rum on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:25:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/rum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trinidaddy Issues</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/trinidaddy-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:25:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/trinidaddy-issues/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A bitter-rich cocktail that adds escapist island notes to the framework of the classic Trinidad Sour.
1 oz Angostura Bitters 1 oz Macadamia Nut Orgeat ¾ oz Jamaican Overproof Rum* ½ oz Acid-adjusted Orange Juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass. No garnish.
*Recommended: Plantation OFTD Overproof
Macadamia Nut Orgeat 1 cup raw macadamia nuts hot (not boiling) water 4 cups white sugar 1 tsp salt ½ oz Orange Blossom Water 1 oz vodka (to fortify) Put the macadamia nuts in a quart-sized Mason jar and fill with hot water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Wind Tea</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/trade-wind-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:49:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/trade-wind-tea/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail This multi-faceted vacation in a glass, gushing with tropical flavor and exotic spice, will treat your taste buds with each sip.
1 ½ oz ‘Black’ Rum* ½ oz Sweet Aged Rum** ½ oz St. Elizabeth’s Allspice Dram ½ oz Ginger Syrup ½ oz Passion Fruit 1 oz lime juice 2 dashes (2 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice into a ceramic Tiki glass and garnish with a dehydrated lime wheel and a paper cocktail umbrella.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Song Bird</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/song-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:40:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/song-bird/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A visually stunning, fruity and floral Daiquiri variation that will sing itself onto your Summer Favorites shortlist.
2 oz ‘White’ Rum* ¾ oz lime juice ¾ oz Blueberry-Lavender-Mint Cordial small pinch of salt Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lime peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shore Leave</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shore-leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:35:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shore-leave/</guid>
      <description>A dialed-in adaptation of the Daiquiri No. 3 that provides clean coconut notes and a saline boost to help you pretend you’re at back at your favorite beach.
1 ½ oz Coconut Oil-washed unaged ‘White’ Rum/Rhum ¼ oz Luxardo Maraschino ½ oz Salted Grapefruit Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a large basil leaf, pressing it into your palms before placement to release its oils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rum Communion</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/rum-communion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:19:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/rum-communion/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Tropical yet rustic, this deluxe Daiquiri variation is just as comfortable being dessert as it is a porch-sipper.
2 oz Brown Butter-washed ‘Gold’ Rum* 1 oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ¾ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lime wheel.
*Recommended: Pusser’s British Navy
Brown Butter-washed Gold Rum 1 750ml bottle ‘Gold’ Rum 1 lb unsalted butter Warning: you will lose about 15% of the original amount of rum in this process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chai Tai</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/chai-tai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:49:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/chai-tai/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spiced, cozy seasonal take on the exotic Trader Vic classic.
1 ½ oz Chai-infused Rum* ½ oz Amaro Nonino ½ oz Dry Curaçao** ½ oz Almond Orgeat 1 oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over crushed ice in a rocks glass. Garnish with a sprig of fresh mint, taking care to squeeze the leaves in your hand before placement in order to release their fragrant oils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Sail</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/age-of-sail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:32:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/age-of-sail/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A boozy cane spirit cocktail with a delicate floral essence and complex undertones of bittersweet citrus.
1 ½ oz Haitian Rhum* 1 ½ oz Contratto Bianco ¼ oz Amaro Montenegro shy ¼ oz Pomegranate Grenadine 3 dashes (3 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into chilled coupe glass. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
