<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savory on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/savory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Savory on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 19:26:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/savory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hot Rye</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/hot-rye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 19:26:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/hot-rye/</guid>
      <description>This one goes with Mexican faire rather well, with a twist: rye whiskey is the base.
* 2 oz Rye (recommend Bulleit) * 3/4 oz Ancho Reyes * Barspoon of chiptole maple syrup * 1 dash of mole bitters Stir with ice. Orange peel garnish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpack Grill</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/backpack-grill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 19:21:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/backpack-grill/</guid>
      <description>This one goes perfectly with a BBQ on a warm summer night.
* 2oz Bourbon (recommend Buffalo Trace) * 3/4 oz Sweet Vermouth * 1/4 oz Maple Syrup * 1 dash of Memphis BBQ bitters Stir with ice. Rim a rocks glass with smoked salt, and pour into that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port Royal</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/port-royal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:13:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/port-royal/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Bracing, tannic, and slightly tropical, this cocktail is an imaginary venture to the history-rich docks of Jamaica in the late 1600’s.
1 ½ oz Ceylon Tea-infused London Dry Gin* ½ oz Sweet Aged Rum** ¾ oz Toasted Coconut Honey ¾ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flat Earth</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:17:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail An earthy, restorative sour with complexity that’ll make you question your own sanity.
1 ½ oz Gin* ¾ oz 80-proof Orange Liqueur** ¾ oz Roasted Walnut Orgeat ½ oz Beet Shrub ½ oz lemon juice 8 dashes (8 ml) Habanero Tincture Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lemon wheel.
*Recommended: Vitae Modern Gin, Aviation, Botanist, Plymouth **Recommended: Vitae Orange Liqueur, Cointreau</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig Sidecar</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/fig-sidecar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:13:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/fig-sidecar/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A rich, improved-upon version of the classic that will pair perfectly with the spirit of the Holidays.
1 ½ oz Fig-infused Cognac* ½ oz Cinnamon-infused 80-proof Orange Liqueur** ½ oz Pedro Ximenez Sherry*** ¾ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Matter</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/dark-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:04:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/dark-matter/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A sour for the dark of heart, featuring deep bitter-rich spice notes - perfect for sipping through those last few lingering days of Winter.
1 ½ oz Chai-infused Rye Whiskey* ½ oz Averna Amaro ¾ oz Blood Orange Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Driver</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/daily-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:58:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/daily-driver/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A simple, reliable interpretation of the Old Fashioned that you’ll get plenty of mileage from.
2 oz Bourbon* ¼ oz Rich Demerara Syrup (2:1 recipe) 8 dashes (8 ml) Blackstrap Bitters 4 dashes (4 ml) Dry Curaçao** Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass with a large cube. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Churchmouse</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/churchmouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:54:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/churchmouse/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A nutty, rustic take on the Whiskey Sour, with a churched-up Barley twist.
2 oz Blended Scotch* ¾ oz Roasted Pistachio Honey ¾ oz Acid-Adjusted Orange Juice ½ oz egg white Add all ingredients to shaker, perform dry shake until egg white is properly frothed. Add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Strain into a chilled coupe glass. Garnish with crushed Pistachios sprinkled over the cocktail’s foam.
*Recommended: Monkey Shoulder, Johnnie Walker Black</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chai Tai</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/chai-tai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:49:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/chai-tai/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spiced, cozy seasonal take on the exotic Trader Vic classic.
1 ½ oz Chai-infused Rum* ½ oz Amaro Nonino ½ oz Dry Curaçao** ½ oz Almond Orgeat 1 oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over crushed ice in a rocks glass. Garnish with a sprig of fresh mint, taking care to squeeze the leaves in your hand before placement in order to release their fragrant oils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baroness</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/baroness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:45:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/baroness/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spirituous cold-weather cocktail that’s accentuated by the toasty caramel malt notes of Brown Ale.
1 ½ oz Bourbon* ¾ oz Averna Amaro ½ oz Brown Ale Syrup 4 dashes (4 ml) Regan’s Orange Bitters No. 6 3 dashes (3 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass with a large cube. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
