<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Summer on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/summer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Summer on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:30:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/summer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zapotechnica</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/zapotechnica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:30:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/zapotechnica/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Fruity and complex, this smoky crowd-pleasing sour goes down way too easy.
2 oz Mezcal* ¼ oz Chartreuse Yellow 1 oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ¾ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.
*Recommended: Del Maguey Vida, El Silencio, Creyente Joven, Banhez Joven Espadín y Barril</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shore Leave</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shore-leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:35:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shore-leave/</guid>
      <description>A dialed-in adaptation of the Daiquiri No. 3 that provides clean coconut notes and a saline boost to help you pretend you’re at back at your favorite beach.
1 ½ oz Coconut Oil-washed unaged ‘White’ Rum/Rhum ¼ oz Luxardo Maraschino ½ oz Salted Grapefruit Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a large basil leaf, pressing it into your palms before placement to release its oils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rum Communion</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/rum-communion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:19:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/rum-communion/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Tropical yet rustic, this deluxe Daiquiri variation is just as comfortable being dessert as it is a porch-sipper.
2 oz Brown Butter-washed ‘Gold’ Rum* 1 oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ¾ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lime wheel.
*Recommended: Pusser’s British Navy
Brown Butter-washed Gold Rum 1 750ml bottle ‘Gold’ Rum 1 lb unsalted butter Warning: you will lose about 15% of the original amount of rum in this process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packmule</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/packmule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:03:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/packmule/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spicy, smoky, loaded take on the Mule.
2 oz Mezcal* ¾ oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ½ oz lime juice 15 dashes (15 ml) Habanero Tincture 2 ½ oz Ginger Beer** Add all ingredients except Ginger Beer to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Add Ginger Beer to the shaken cocktail. Double-strain over new ice in copper or tin mule mug. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some Cayenne Salt (equal parts kosher salt and cayenne pepper)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oaxaca Bramble</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/oaxaca-bramble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:57:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/oaxaca-bramble/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Smoke, spice and berries make this a perfect pairing for a barbecue. Best enjoyed outside with friends.
1 oz 100% Agave Reposado Tequila* ½ oz Cinnamon-infused 80-Proof Orange Liqueur** ½ oz Mezcal*** ¾ oz lime juice 1 oz Blackberry Cordial Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a skewered blackberry and a lime wheel.
* Recommended: Altos Olmeca Reposado, Lunazul Reposado, Corralejo Reposado, Herradura Reposado **Recommended: Cointreau, Patrón Citrónge ***Recommended: Del Maguey Vida, El Silencio, Creyente Joven, Banhez Joven Espadín y Barril</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inca Trail</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/inca-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:28:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/inca-trail/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A polished version of the tart classic Pisco Sour that will transport your senses straight to the Andes.
2 oz Peruvian Pisco* ¾ oz Lime Cordial ½ oz lime juice ½ oz egg white Add all ingredients to shaker, perform dry shake until egg white is properly frothed. Add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Strain into a chilled coupe glass. Garnish with nutmeg grated over the foam.
*Recommended: La Diablada, Macchu Pisco</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farmers Tan</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/farmers-tan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:08:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/farmers-tan/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A refreshingly acidic pick-me-up to ease you through the hottest days of Summer.
2 oz Lemongrass-infused Corn Moonshine* 1 oz Watermelon Shrub ¾ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lime wheel.
*Recommended: Belle Isle Moonshine
Lemongrass-infused Corn Moonshine 750ml bottle Corn Moonshine 8 stalks of lemongrass Slice the lemongrass into small pieces, then combine with the Moonshine in a quart-sized Mason jar and let infuse for three days, agitating daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jungle Cat</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/jungle-cat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/jungle-cat/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A smoky twist on the bitter Tiki darling the Jungle Bird, with a touch of dry heat and ample complexity from the addition of spice to the classic framework.
1 ½ oz Mezcal* ¾ oz Campari 1 ¼ oz pineapple juice ½ oz lime juice ¾ oz Caribbean Jerk Syrup Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in a Collins glass.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
