<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Floral on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/floral/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Floral on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:40:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/floral/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Song Bird</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/song-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:40:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/song-bird/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A visually stunning, fruity and floral Daiquiri variation that will sing itself onto your Summer Favorites shortlist.
2 oz ‘White’ Rum* ¾ oz lime juice ¾ oz Blueberry-Lavender-Mint Cordial small pinch of salt Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lime peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Fiction</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/historical-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:25:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/historical-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A floral, refreshing cocktail that captures both the imagination and the senses.
1 ½ oz Gin* ½ oz Rosebud-infused Aquavit** 12 drops of Suze Gentian Liqueur*** 1 oz Raspberry Cordial ¾ oz lemon juice ½ oz egg white Add all ingredients to shaker, perform dry shake until egg white is properly frothed. Add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Strain into a chilled coupe glass. Garnish with bitter hearts (use an eye-dropper bottle filled with Angostura Bitters to place drops on the foam, and then drag a toothpick through them from one side through the other to make a heart shape) and rosebuds floated on the foam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Sail</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/age-of-sail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:32:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/age-of-sail/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A boozy cane spirit cocktail with a delicate floral essence and complex undertones of bittersweet citrus.
1 ½ oz Haitian Rhum* 1 ½ oz Contratto Bianco ¼ oz Amaro Montenegro shy ¼ oz Pomegranate Grenadine 3 dashes (3 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into chilled coupe glass. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
