<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cocktail Recipes on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cocktail Recipes on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 15:51:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hot Rye</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/hot-rye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 19:26:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/hot-rye/</guid>
      <description>This one goes with Mexican faire rather well, with a twist: rye whiskey is the base.
* 2 oz Rye (recommend Bulleit) * 3/4 oz Ancho Reyes * Barspoon of chiptole maple syrup * 1 dash of mole bitters Stir with ice. Orange peel garnish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpack Grill</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/backpack-grill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 19:21:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/backpack-grill/</guid>
      <description>This one goes perfectly with a BBQ on a warm summer night.
* 2oz Bourbon (recommend Buffalo Trace) * 3/4 oz Sweet Vermouth * 1/4 oz Maple Syrup * 1 dash of Memphis BBQ bitters Stir with ice. Rim a rocks glass with smoked salt, and pour into that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gomme</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/gomme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 18:28:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/gomme/</guid>
      <description>Gomme syrup is made with gum arabic, and imparts 2 qualities to any cocktail made with it:
Any alcohol burn or off-taste is reduced slightly. It will not hide bottom-shelf trash, but it will smooth out an edge if there is one. It brings ingredients a little closer to balance. The texture is thickened, bringing to mind a smoother, almost silk-like texture. This recipe is the rich version, treat it like a 2:1 simple syrup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocktail Templates</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 18:20:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/templates/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re ever up for trying something new, or just really lazy, these template recipes for drinks will almost always yield something interesting. Use them a few times with different ingredients to figure out what you really like.
Basic Cocktail * 1 teaspoon of Simple Syrup * 2oz of any base spirit (gin, vodka, tequila, whiskey, whisky, brandy, or rum) * 2 dashes of bitters * 1/2 teaspoon of Cointreau Stir together with ice, and then express a lemon peel over it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zapotechnica</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/zapotechnica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:30:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/zapotechnica/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Fruity and complex, this smoky crowd-pleasing sour goes down way too easy.
2 oz Mezcal* ¼ oz Chartreuse Yellow 1 oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ¾ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.
*Recommended: Del Maguey Vida, El Silencio, Creyente Joven, Banhez Joven Espadín y Barril</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trinidaddy Issues</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/trinidaddy-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:25:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/trinidaddy-issues/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A bitter-rich cocktail that adds escapist island notes to the framework of the classic Trinidad Sour.
1 oz Angostura Bitters 1 oz Macadamia Nut Orgeat ¾ oz Jamaican Overproof Rum* ½ oz Acid-adjusted Orange Juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass. No garnish.
*Recommended: Plantation OFTD Overproof
Macadamia Nut Orgeat 1 cup raw macadamia nuts hot (not boiling) water 4 cups white sugar 1 tsp salt ½ oz Orange Blossom Water 1 oz vodka (to fortify) Put the macadamia nuts in a quart-sized Mason jar and fill with hot water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Wind Tea</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/trade-wind-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:49:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/trade-wind-tea/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail This multi-faceted vacation in a glass, gushing with tropical flavor and exotic spice, will treat your taste buds with each sip.
1 ½ oz ‘Black’ Rum* ½ oz Sweet Aged Rum** ½ oz St. Elizabeth’s Allspice Dram ½ oz Ginger Syrup ½ oz Passion Fruit 1 oz lime juice 2 dashes (2 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice into a ceramic Tiki glass and garnish with a dehydrated lime wheel and a paper cocktail umbrella.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stowaway</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/stowaway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:45:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/stowaway/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail This beach-y, fruity cocktail is a light-hearted crowd-pleaser that evokes the feeling of a Piña Colada - but without all the mess.
1 ½ oz Coconut Oil-washed Potato Vodka* ½ oz Dry Curaçao** ¾ oz Guava ¾ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in a Collins glass and garnish with a dehydrated lime wheel and a paper cocktail umbrella.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Song Bird</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/song-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:40:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/song-bird/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A visually stunning, fruity and floral Daiquiri variation that will sing itself onto your Summer Favorites shortlist.
2 oz ‘White’ Rum* ¾ oz lime juice ¾ oz Blueberry-Lavender-Mint Cordial small pinch of salt Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lime peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shore Leave</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shore-leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:35:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shore-leave/</guid>
      <description>A dialed-in adaptation of the Daiquiri No. 3 that provides clean coconut notes and a saline boost to help you pretend you’re at back at your favorite beach.
1 ½ oz Coconut Oil-washed unaged ‘White’ Rum/Rhum ¼ oz Luxardo Maraschino ½ oz Salted Grapefruit Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a large basil leaf, pressing it into your palms before placement to release its oils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shoegaze</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shoegaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:29:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shoegaze/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A multi-layered cocktail with fruit, spice, and juniper working in tandem to let you experience a Wall of Flavor.
1 ½ oz London Dry Gin* 1 oz Szechuan Peppercorn-infused Byrrh Quinquina 1 oz Strawberry Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a fresh strawberry.
*Recommended: Bombay Sapphire
Szechuan Peppercorn-infused Byrrh Quinquina ½ cup Szechuan Peppercorns, crushed 750ml bottle Byrrh Quinquina Combine the Szechuan Peppercorns and the Byrrh in a quart-sized Mason jar and infuse for 48 hours, agitating daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shieldmaiden</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shieldmaiden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:26:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shieldmaiden/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail An adventurous Nordic-inspired riff on the Gimlet that incorporates the gentle cooling qualities of sage into the harsher tones of caraway and citrus.
1 oz Aquavit* 1 oz London Dry Gin** 1 oz Lemon-Sage Cordial ¼ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lemon wheel and a sage leaf.
*Recommended: Linie, Krogstad **Recommended: Fords, Bombay Dry, Broker’s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Puppet</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shadow-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:24:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shadow-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A dark, moody tipple with rich botanical undertones and a hint of menthol on its finish.
1 ½ oz Rye Whiskey* ¾ oz Cardamaro** ½ oz Pedro Ximenez Sherry*** shy ¼ oz Fernet Branca 4 dashes (4 ml) Peychaud’s Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass over new ice. Garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rum Communion</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/rum-communion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:19:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/rum-communion/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Tropical yet rustic, this deluxe Daiquiri variation is just as comfortable being dessert as it is a porch-sipper.
2 oz Brown Butter-washed ‘Gold’ Rum* 1 oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ¾ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lime wheel.
*Recommended: Pusser’s British Navy
Brown Butter-washed Gold Rum 1 750ml bottle ‘Gold’ Rum 1 lb unsalted butter Warning: you will lose about 15% of the original amount of rum in this process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port Royal</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/port-royal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:13:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/port-royal/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Bracing, tannic, and slightly tropical, this cocktail is an imaginary venture to the history-rich docks of Jamaica in the late 1600’s.
1 ½ oz Ceylon Tea-infused London Dry Gin* ½ oz Sweet Aged Rum** ¾ oz Toasted Coconut Honey ¾ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junction Paloma</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/junction-paloma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:08:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/junction-paloma/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Salty, refreshing and effervescent, this non-traditional take on the Mexican classic is sure to be a crowd-pleaser.
1 ½ oz 100% Agave Blanco Tequila* ½ oz Aperol ½ oz lime juice ¾ oz Salted Grapefruit Cordial 1 oz still water Assemble all ingredients, add ice, then carbonate**. Shake, then strain into a champagne flute. No garnish.
* Recommended: Lunazul Blanco, Altos Olmeca Blanco, Espolòn Blanco, Herradura Silver ** Note: I use the Perlini Cocktail Cabonation System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packmule</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/packmule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:03:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/packmule/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spicy, smoky, loaded take on the Mule.
2 oz Mezcal* ¾ oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ½ oz lime juice 15 dashes (15 ml) Habanero Tincture 2 ½ oz Ginger Beer** Add all ingredients except Ginger Beer to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Add Ginger Beer to the shaken cocktail. Double-strain over new ice in copper or tin mule mug. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some Cayenne Salt (equal parts kosher salt and cayenne pepper)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oaxaca Bramble</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/oaxaca-bramble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:57:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/oaxaca-bramble/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Smoke, spice and berries make this a perfect pairing for a barbecue. Best enjoyed outside with friends.
1 oz 100% Agave Reposado Tequila* ½ oz Cinnamon-infused 80-Proof Orange Liqueur** ½ oz Mezcal*** ¾ oz lime juice 1 oz Blackberry Cordial Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a skewered blackberry and a lime wheel.
* Recommended: Altos Olmeca Reposado, Lunazul Reposado, Corralejo Reposado, Herradura Reposado **Recommended: Cointreau, Patrón Citrónge ***Recommended: Del Maguey Vida, El Silencio, Creyente Joven, Banhez Joven Espadín y Barril</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monkey Island</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/monkey-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:53:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/monkey-island/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A fruity yet spirit-forward cocktail with tropical notes that blur the imaginary lines dividing the seasons.
2 oz Blended Speyside Scotch* ½ oz Tempus Fugit Crème de Banane ½ oz Toasted Coconut Honey 6 dashes (6 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass with a large cube. Garnish with a dehydrated lime wheel.
*Recommended: Monkey Shoulder</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luchador</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/luchador/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:44:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/luchador/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A light-hearted prize-fighter that will win over almost any modern drinker.
1 ½ oz 100% Agave Blanco Tequila* ¾ oz Ancho Reyes Chili Liqueur ¾ oz lime juice ¾ oz Prickly Pear Cactus ¼ oz Ginger Syrup Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L&#39;Appel Du Vide</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/l-appel-du-vide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:40:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/l-appel-du-vide/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A rich, acidic stirred cocktail with roundness and immediacy that will call you back from edge of The Void.
1 ½ oz Cognac* ¾ oz Fig-Balsamic Shrub ½ oz Pedro Ximenez Sherry** ¼ oz Cynar 2 dashes (2 ml) Fee Brothers Old Fashioned Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass over new ice. Garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jungle Cat</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/jungle-cat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:31:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/jungle-cat/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A smoky twist on the bitter Tiki darling the Jungle Bird, with a touch of dry heat and ample complexity from the addition of spice to the classic framework.
1 ½ oz Mezcal* ¾ oz Campari 1 ¼ oz pineapple juice ½ oz lime juice ¾ oz Caribbean Jerk Syrup Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in a Collins glass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inca Trail</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/inca-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:28:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/inca-trail/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A polished version of the tart classic Pisco Sour that will transport your senses straight to the Andes.
2 oz Peruvian Pisco* ¾ oz Lime Cordial ½ oz lime juice ½ oz egg white Add all ingredients to shaker, perform dry shake until egg white is properly frothed. Add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Strain into a chilled coupe glass. Garnish with nutmeg grated over the foam.
*Recommended: La Diablada, Macchu Pisco</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Fiction</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/historical-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:25:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/historical-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A floral, refreshing cocktail that captures both the imagination and the senses.
1 ½ oz Gin* ½ oz Rosebud-infused Aquavit** 12 drops of Suze Gentian Liqueur*** 1 oz Raspberry Cordial ¾ oz lemon juice ½ oz egg white Add all ingredients to shaker, perform dry shake until egg white is properly frothed. Add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Strain into a chilled coupe glass. Garnish with bitter hearts (use an eye-dropper bottle filled with Angostura Bitters to place drops on the foam, and then drag a toothpick through them from one side through the other to make a heart shape) and rosebuds floated on the foam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Hell to Breakfast</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/from-hell-to-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:22:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/from-hell-to-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>A hint of subtle spice lingers just underneath the surface of this rejuvenating and herbaceous sour that offers more with each sip.
1 oz 100-proof Rye Whiskey* ¾ oz Bénédictine D.O.M. ½ oz Luxardo Maraschino ¾ oz lemon juice 6 dashes (6 ml) St. Elizabeth’s Allspice Dram Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flat Earth</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:17:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/flat-earth/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail An earthy, restorative sour with complexity that’ll make you question your own sanity.
1 ½ oz Gin* ¾ oz 80-proof Orange Liqueur** ¾ oz Roasted Walnut Orgeat ½ oz Beet Shrub ½ oz lemon juice 8 dashes (8 ml) Habanero Tincture Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lemon wheel.
*Recommended: Vitae Modern Gin, Aviation, Botanist, Plymouth **Recommended: Vitae Orange Liqueur, Cointreau</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig Sidecar</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/fig-sidecar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:13:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/fig-sidecar/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A rich, improved-upon version of the classic that will pair perfectly with the spirit of the Holidays.
1 ½ oz Fig-infused Cognac* ½ oz Cinnamon-infused 80-proof Orange Liqueur** ½ oz Pedro Ximenez Sherry*** ¾ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farmers Tan</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/farmers-tan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:08:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/farmers-tan/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A refreshingly acidic pick-me-up to ease you through the hottest days of Summer.
2 oz Lemongrass-infused Corn Moonshine* 1 oz Watermelon Shrub ¾ oz lemon juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a floating lime wheel.
*Recommended: Belle Isle Moonshine
Lemongrass-infused Corn Moonshine 750ml bottle Corn Moonshine 8 stalks of lemongrass Slice the lemongrass into small pieces, then combine with the Moonshine in a quart-sized Mason jar and let infuse for three days, agitating daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Matter</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/dark-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:04:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/dark-matter/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A sour for the dark of heart, featuring deep bitter-rich spice notes - perfect for sipping through those last few lingering days of Winter.
1 ½ oz Chai-infused Rye Whiskey* ½ oz Averna Amaro ¾ oz Blood Orange Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Driver</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/daily-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:58:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/daily-driver/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A simple, reliable interpretation of the Old Fashioned that you’ll get plenty of mileage from.
2 oz Bourbon* ¼ oz Rich Demerara Syrup (2:1 recipe) 8 dashes (8 ml) Blackstrap Bitters 4 dashes (4 ml) Dry Curaçao** Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass with a large cube. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Churchmouse</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/churchmouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:54:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/churchmouse/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A nutty, rustic take on the Whiskey Sour, with a churched-up Barley twist.
2 oz Blended Scotch* ¾ oz Roasted Pistachio Honey ¾ oz Acid-Adjusted Orange Juice ½ oz egg white Add all ingredients to shaker, perform dry shake until egg white is properly frothed. Add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Strain into a chilled coupe glass. Garnish with crushed Pistachios sprinkled over the cocktail’s foam.
*Recommended: Monkey Shoulder, Johnnie Walker Black</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chai Tai</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/chai-tai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:49:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/chai-tai/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spiced, cozy seasonal take on the exotic Trader Vic classic.
1 ½ oz Chai-infused Rum* ½ oz Amaro Nonino ½ oz Dry Curaçao** ½ oz Almond Orgeat 1 oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over crushed ice in a rocks glass. Garnish with a sprig of fresh mint, taking care to squeeze the leaves in your hand before placement in order to release their fragrant oils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baroness</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/baroness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:45:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/baroness/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spirituous cold-weather cocktail that’s accentuated by the toasty caramel malt notes of Brown Ale.
1 ½ oz Bourbon* ¾ oz Averna Amaro ½ oz Brown Ale Syrup 4 dashes (4 ml) Regan’s Orange Bitters No. 6 3 dashes (3 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass with a large cube. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appaloosa</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/appaloosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:40:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/appaloosa/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spicy, lively sour with a velvety mouthfeel and a ‘green’, vegetal flavor profile.
1 ½ oz 100% Agave Reposado Tequila* ¾ oz Ancho Reyes Verde Chili Liqueur 1 oz lime juice ½ oz Pepita Orgeat Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Sail</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/age-of-sail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:32:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/age-of-sail/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A boozy cane spirit cocktail with a delicate floral essence and complex undertones of bittersweet citrus.
1 ½ oz Haitian Rhum* 1 ½ oz Contratto Bianco ¼ oz Amaro Montenegro shy ¼ oz Pomegranate Grenadine 3 dashes (3 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into chilled coupe glass. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
