<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whiskey on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/whiskey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whiskey on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 19:26:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/tags/whiskey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hot Rye</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/hot-rye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 19:26:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/hot-rye/</guid>
      <description>This one goes with Mexican faire rather well, with a twist: rye whiskey is the base.
* 2 oz Rye (recommend Bulleit) * 3/4 oz Ancho Reyes * Barspoon of chiptole maple syrup * 1 dash of mole bitters Stir with ice. Orange peel garnish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpack Grill</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/backpack-grill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 19:21:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/backpack-grill/</guid>
      <description>This one goes perfectly with a BBQ on a warm summer night.
* 2oz Bourbon (recommend Buffalo Trace) * 3/4 oz Sweet Vermouth * 1/4 oz Maple Syrup * 1 dash of Memphis BBQ bitters Stir with ice. Rim a rocks glass with smoked salt, and pour into that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Puppet</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shadow-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:24:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/shadow-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A dark, moody tipple with rich botanical undertones and a hint of menthol on its finish.
1 ½ oz Rye Whiskey* ¾ oz Cardamaro** ½ oz Pedro Ximenez Sherry*** shy ¼ oz Fernet Branca 4 dashes (4 ml) Peychaud’s Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass over new ice. Garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Hell to Breakfast</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/from-hell-to-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:22:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/from-hell-to-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>A hint of subtle spice lingers just underneath the surface of this rejuvenating and herbaceous sour that offers more with each sip.
1 oz 100-proof Rye Whiskey* ¾ oz Bénédictine D.O.M. ½ oz Luxardo Maraschino ¾ oz lemon juice 6 dashes (6 ml) St. Elizabeth’s Allspice Dram Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with a lemon peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Matter</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/dark-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:04:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/dark-matter/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A sour for the dark of heart, featuring deep bitter-rich spice notes - perfect for sipping through those last few lingering days of Winter.
1 ½ oz Chai-infused Rye Whiskey* ½ oz Averna Amaro ¾ oz Blood Orange Cordial ½ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain into a chilled coupe glass and garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express the citrus oil over the edge and stem of the glass, and across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Driver</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/daily-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:58:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/daily-driver/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A simple, reliable interpretation of the Old Fashioned that you’ll get plenty of mileage from.
2 oz Bourbon* ¼ oz Rich Demerara Syrup (2:1 recipe) 8 dashes (8 ml) Blackstrap Bitters 4 dashes (4 ml) Dry Curaçao** Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass with a large cube. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baroness</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/baroness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:45:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/baroness/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spirituous cold-weather cocktail that’s accentuated by the toasty caramel malt notes of Brown Ale.
1 ½ oz Bourbon* ¾ oz Averna Amaro ½ oz Brown Ale Syrup 4 dashes (4 ml) Regan’s Orange Bitters No. 6 3 dashes (3 ml) Angostura Bitters Add all ingredients to a mixing glass, add ice, gently stir until properly chilled. Strain into rocks glass with a large cube. Garnish with an orange peel, taking care to express its citrus oil across the surface of the drink.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
