<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tequila on Jay&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/tequila/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tequila on Jay&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:30:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zyzyx.github.io/flavors/tequila/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zapotechnica</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/zapotechnica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 15:30:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/zapotechnica/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Fruity and complex, this smoky crowd-pleasing sour goes down way too easy.
2 oz Mezcal* ¼ oz Chartreuse Yellow 1 oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ¾ oz lime juice Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.
*Recommended: Del Maguey Vida, El Silencio, Creyente Joven, Banhez Joven Espadín y Barril</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junction Paloma</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/junction-paloma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:08:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/junction-paloma/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Salty, refreshing and effervescent, this non-traditional take on the Mexican classic is sure to be a crowd-pleaser.
1 ½ oz 100% Agave Blanco Tequila* ½ oz Aperol ½ oz lime juice ¾ oz Salted Grapefruit Cordial 1 oz still water Assemble all ingredients, add ice, then carbonate**. Shake, then strain into a champagne flute. No garnish.
* Recommended: Lunazul Blanco, Altos Olmeca Blanco, Espolòn Blanco, Herradura Silver ** Note: I use the Perlini Cocktail Cabonation System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packmule</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/packmule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 22:03:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/packmule/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spicy, smoky, loaded take on the Mule.
2 oz Mezcal* ¾ oz Grilled Pineapple Cordial ½ oz lime juice 15 dashes (15 ml) Habanero Tincture 2 ½ oz Ginger Beer** Add all ingredients except Ginger Beer to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Add Ginger Beer to the shaken cocktail. Double-strain over new ice in copper or tin mule mug. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some Cayenne Salt (equal parts kosher salt and cayenne pepper)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oaxaca Bramble</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/oaxaca-bramble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:57:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/oaxaca-bramble/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail Smoke, spice and berries make this a perfect pairing for a barbecue. Best enjoyed outside with friends.
1 oz 100% Agave Reposado Tequila* ½ oz Cinnamon-infused 80-Proof Orange Liqueur** ½ oz Mezcal*** ¾ oz lime juice 1 oz Blackberry Cordial Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a skewered blackberry and a lime wheel.
* Recommended: Altos Olmeca Reposado, Lunazul Reposado, Corralejo Reposado, Herradura Reposado **Recommended: Cointreau, Patrón Citrónge ***Recommended: Del Maguey Vida, El Silencio, Creyente Joven, Banhez Joven Espadín y Barril</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luchador</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/luchador/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 21:44:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/luchador/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A light-hearted prize-fighter that will win over almost any modern drinker.
1 ½ oz 100% Agave Blanco Tequila* ¾ oz Ancho Reyes Chili Liqueur ¾ oz lime juice ¾ oz Prickly Pear Cactus ¼ oz Ginger Syrup Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appaloosa</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/appaloosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:40:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/appaloosa/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A spicy, lively sour with a velvety mouthfeel and a ‘green’, vegetal flavor profile.
1 ½ oz 100% Agave Reposado Tequila* ¾ oz Ancho Reyes Verde Chili Liqueur 1 oz lime juice ½ oz Pepita Orgeat Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in rocks glass. Garnish with a lime wheel perched on top of the drink, sprinkled with some finishing salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jungle Cat</title>
      <link>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/jungle-cat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://zyzyx.github.io/drinking/jungle-cat/</guid>
      <description>Cocktail A smoky twist on the bitter Tiki darling the Jungle Bird, with a touch of dry heat and ample complexity from the addition of spice to the classic framework.
1 ½ oz Mezcal* ¾ oz Campari 1 ¼ oz pineapple juice ½ oz lime juice ¾ oz Caribbean Jerk Syrup Add all ingredients to shaker, add ice, shake vigorously until properly chilled. Double-strain over new ice in a Collins glass.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
